<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml>
    <block n="1">1 Every October it becomes important, no, necessary to see the <nature>leaves
            turning</nature>, to be <nature>surrounded by leaves turning</nature>; it's not just the
        symbolism, to <feeling>confront in the death of the year your death</feeling>, one blazing
        farewell appearance, though the irony isn't lost on <pronoun>you</pronoun> that nature is
        most seductive when it's about to die, flaunting the dazzle of its incipient exit, an ending
        that at least so far the effects of human progress <mandis>(pollution, acid rain)</mandis>
        <feeling> have not yet frightened <pronoun>you</pronoun> enough to make
                <pronoun>you</pronoun> believe is real</feeling>; that is, <pronoun>you</pronoun>
        know this ending is a deception because of course nature is always renewing itself— the
        trees don't die, <pronoun>they</pronoun> just pretend, go out in style, and return in style:
        a new style.</block>
    <block n="2">2 Is it deliberate how far <pronoun>they</pronoun> make <pronoun>you</pronoun> go
        especially if <pronoun>you</pronoun>live in the city to get far enough away from home to see
        not just trees but only trees? The boring highways, roadsigns, high speeds, 10-axle trucks
        passing you as if they were in an even greater hurry than you to look at leaves: so you
        drive in <feeling>terro</feeling>r for literal hours and it looks like
            <weather>rain</weather>, or <weather>snow</weather>, but it's probably just clouds (too
        cloudy to see any color?) and <pronoun>you</pronoun> wonder, given the poverty of
            <pronoun>your</pronoun> memory, which road had the most color last year, but it doesn't
        matter since <pronoun>you're</pronoun> probably too late anyway, or too early— whichever
        road <pronoun>you</pronoun> take will be the wrong one and you've probably come all this way
        for nothing.</block>
    <block n="3">3 <pronoun>You'll</pronoun> be driving along <feeling>depressed</feeling> when
        suddenly a cloud will move and the sun will muscle through and ignite the hills. It may not
        last. Probably won't last. But for a moment the whole world comes to. Wakes up. Proves it
        lives. It lives— <color>red</color>, <color>yellow</color>, <color>orange</color>,
            <color>brown</color>, <color>russet</color>, <color>ocher</color>,
            <color>vermilion</color>, <color>gold</color>. <element>Flame</element> and rust.
            <element>Flame</element> and rust, the permutations of burning.
            <pronoun>You're</pronoun> on <element>fire</element>. <pronoun>You</pronoun>r eyes are
        on <element>fire</element>. It won't last, you don't want it to last. <pronoun>You</pronoun>
        can't stand any more. But <pronoun>you</pronoun> don't want it to stop. It's what
            <pronoun>you've</pronoun> come for. It's what <pronoun>you'll</pronoun> come back for.
        It won't stay with <pronoun>you</pronoun>, but <pronoun>you'll</pronoun> remember that it
        felt like nothing else <pronoun>you've</pronoun> felt or something <pronoun>you've</pronoun>
        felt that also didn't last.</block>
</xml>
